ASHTON MONZI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

Prior to starting at Nashville Software School, I was a senior graphic designer with 6 years of industry experience. I became interested in software development after getting hands-on experience during my time at a Nashville creative agency. It was there that I realized how much I enjoyed applying the creativity from graphic design to a more technical field. This interest led me to Nashville Software School's Web Development Jumpstart course where I could utilize my attention to detail and problem-solving abilities. That experience showed me I wanted to be in a field that, along with promoting continual growth, didn't shy away from the How and Why of a project.

INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS

BARKBOOK - FRONT-END CAPSTONE

Barkbook helps find a playmate for your pet by allowing the user to search a specific neighborhood of Davidson County. The user can then connect with another user via direct message to set up a play date without leaving the house. Fido finds a mate that matches their size and energy and you meet new people.

- Full CRUD React application utilizing React hooks to manage state
- JSON server used as local database
- Styled with CSS3
- Cloudinary API used for image uploading

barkbook.app/login use demo@barkbook.com for quick login

STRESSLESS - BACK-END CAPSTONE

StressLess is a full-stack application aimed at helping high-performing individuals tackle their stress by creating habits that aid in self-care. The app will help bring more awareness to prioritizing themselves, rather than focusing on the ever-evolving demands around them. A community of like-minded individuals will also be in their reach for support and accountability.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, React, Python, Django, SQLite3 coming soon!

- **(**615) 419-5771
- ashtonsnow48@gmail.com
- ashtonsnow.com
- in <u>linkedin</u>
- github

SKILLS

- Javascript
- Python
- Illustrator CC

- React
- Django
- Photoshop CC

- HTML
- SQL
- InDesign CC

- CSS
- Git/GitHub
- Illustration

- Bootstrap
- Scrum/Agile

TECHNICAL EDUCATION

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nasvhille Software School | APR 2021 - SEPT 2021

Intensive full-time 6-month software development Bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects. Tech Stack: Python/Django; React.js; JavaScript; HTML5; CSS3; SQL fundamentals.

- Utilized Git and Github for version control
- Simulated work-based learning environment
- Emphasis on team-based development in an agile workflow
- · Applied knowledge of interpreting existing code

GROUP PROJECTS

TRUNCHEONS & FLAGONS

- Tools Used: Javascript, JSON, CSS, HTML
- Worked with a team of four to create a component-based game application using SCRUM framework
- Participated in pair programming to render leaderboard component, game data with fetch calls to local database on JSON server, and CSS styling of the application
- Took lead on database management and migrations
- Shared responsibility in project planning, SCRUM workflow, MVP integrity, and a constructive Retrospective
- Coordinated with the team to utilize GitHub as source-control for smooth integration of modular components
- Interactive site deployed on DigitalOcean
- truncheons-flagons.app/

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER | PRODUCT DEVELOPER

The Clever Factory | APR 2020 - MAR 2021

Designed kids' games, activities, every day and seasonal products from initial concept sketches through to the final product and packaging. These products were for global distribution by major retailers such as Target, Walmart, Aldi, and more.

- Took lead on game board development with brainstorming, research, and concept sketches
- Illustrated and created logotypes for packaging
- Product & package concept & design
 Concept Sketches, Illustrator CC, Photoshop CC
- Maintained a balanced workflow in a fast-paced environment

Organization, Multi-tasking, Flexibility

- · Completed projects ahead of or by deadline
- Setting up files for prepress InDesign CC, Illustrator CC

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

The Clever Factory | JUN 2018 - APR 2020

Designed kids' games, activities, every day and seasonal products from initial concept sketches through to the final product and packaging. These products were for global distribution by major retailers such as Target, Walmart, Aldi, and more.

- Designed kids' activities and stickers
 Research, Critical Thinking, Brainstorming
- Illustrated and created logotypes for packaging
- Maintained a balanced workflow in a fast-paced environment
- Completed projects ahead of or by deadline
- · Setting up files for prepress

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Certificate of Software Development

BETHEL UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science Management and Organizational Development

FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Locomotion Creative | OCT 2017 - APR 2018

Provided support to designers and the web development team by developing designs and marketing assets. Acquired insight into the business of an advertising agency.

- Web design & front-end development HTML5, CSS, PHP, WordPress CMS
- · Social media content creation & analytics
- Designed brochures, newsletters, and apparel
- Provided support in photo retouching and mockups

LEAD GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Francis Communications, Inc. | Arena Imprints AUG 2014 - OCT 2017

- Directed production art for all in-house screen printing projects with orders in excess of 2500 pieces
- · Managed designers in absence of Director
- Increased production art output Executed designs under budget
- Improved & managed final approval of onpress projects
- Initiated & organized team meetings to improve communication & collaboration amongst the art department

Trained designers in prepress setup

- Completed tasks within tight timelines; Flexibility, Communication, Collaboration
- Packaged and preflight files for release to outside vendors, printers, & other media partners
- Designed vector & raster graphic elements & illustrations for apparel Illustrator CC, Photoshop CC

ASSISTANT SHOP MANAGER | AUTOMATIC PRESS OPERATOR

Francis Communications, Inc. | Arena Imprints MAY 2012 - SEPT 2014

- Managed, trained, and led 20 hourly associates
- Assisted with supervising all plant operations
- Checked all work in progress for detail and quality specifications
- Managed priority of orders and operating schedules as work requirements demanded
- · Maintained a safe and clean work environment
- Maintained and operated complex 14 and 16 color automatic printing presses
- Ordered supplies for shop use